[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "What to Expect During Your F-1 Visa Interview",
        "answer": "Our guide provides a list of answers to possible questions for the student visa interview, covering the most common F-1 visa interview questions you can expect at your embassy or consulate. You can learn more aboutF-1 student visasby visiting theU.S. Department of State website.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "How To Dress for Your F-1 Visa Interview",
        "answer": "First impressions are always important, so think carefully aboutwhat to wear for the US visa interview. Choosing the right attire can highlight your professionalism and seriousness. While there are no written rules on what to wear for your visa interview, there are standard norms and expectations you should follow. Here are some tips for appropriate interview clothing and styling.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Documents You Need for the Interview",
        "answer": "You must bring specific documents with you when you go for your F-1 visa interview. These documents include:",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Your Study Plans in the United States",
        "answer": "The interviewer will be interested in knowing why you chose the US for university, what you plan to study in the US, and more. These questions will be similar to the questions on your university application essays.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Common Study Plan Questions and Answers",
        "answer": "Here is a list of possible F-1 visa interview questions on your study plans in the United States.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Why You Chose the University You Are Planning to Attend",
        "answer": "By asking F-1 visa interview questions about your university choices in the US, the visa officer expects to understand your academic skills and why you chose the university you wish to attend. Do not forget that international students that are accepted by top-ranked universities will have better chances for aF-1 student visa.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Common University Questions and Answers",
        "answer": "Here are some US F-1 visa interview questions that cover why you chose the university you wish to attend in the US.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Your Academic History and Record of Achievements",
        "answer": "Even though you have already been accepted at a US college or university, the interviewer may still want to know if you are capable of being successful in your studies in the US. Your interviewer may ask you to share your test scores, English language proficiency levels, and/or high school transcripts. These factors will help them determine whether you will be able to excel as a student in the institution you wish to attend.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Common Academic History Questions and Answers",
        "answer": "Here are some F-1 student visa interview questions and answers on your academic history and record of achievements.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Your Finances",
        "answer": "Proving financial stability is required to get yourUS student visa. In order to issue your F-1 visa, your visa officer will want to see that you have enough funds to live in the US as an international student and pay for your education. Your financial plan should include expenses like tuition fees, housing, dining,health insurance, and transportation. If you havea sponsorwho will help with your expenses, the visa officer will likely ask questions about how you are related to the sponsor.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "Common Financial Questions and Answers",
        "answer": "Here is a list of questions the visa interviewer may ask about your financial stability that the visa interviewer may ask.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "Your Post-Graduation Plans",
        "answer": "While you may be interested in working in the US after graduation, you have to highlight that you wish to return to your home country after you finish your degree program. Plan to talk to your visa officer about why you want to return to your home country after graduation.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Common Post-Graduation Questions and Answers",
        "answer": "Here are some immigration interview questions you could be asked about your post-graduation plans.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "How Can You Begin Preparing for Your F-1 Visa Interview?",
        "answer": "There are more than one million international students studying in the US, and they all had to go through a visa interview, just like you. Stay calm, practice answering the American visa questions for students in your own words, and make sure you have all the necessary materials in order and with you on your interview day.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "Services that set you up for success",
        "answer": "Our personalized programs support international students from application to enrollment, while Signature universities offer enhanced admissions, visa, academic, and career services, including our award-winning Accelerator Programs.**Services vary by school.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "Research",
        "answer": "Answer not available.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "Admissions",
        "answer": "Answer not available.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "Enrollment",
        "answer": "Answer not available.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "On Campus",
        "answer": "Answer not available.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "Academics",
        "answer": "Answer not available.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "question": "Career",
        "answer": "Answer not available.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "question": "Helping international students study at top US universities",
        "answer": "\n\n\n",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "question": "Quick F1 Visa Interview Tips",
        "answer": "Answer the questions clearly, do not take a lot of time to think, since the interview is short.\nProvide the consular with all the documents he requires to see. Organize your documents prior to your visa interview so you will not have a total mess in your hands when you go at the embassy/consulate.\nKeep calm, and try to avoid drinking any alcohol at least 24 hours before your interview.\nOn the day of the interview eat before going to the appointment center, since sometimes you might have to wait a bit longer than foreseen.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "question": "What Are the Most Common F1 Visa Interview Questions?",
        "answer": "The consular officers usually ask similar questions to every F1 visa candidate. This is in your favor since it helps you prepare in advance. Usually, the interviewer asks you questions related to your:",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "question": "Why are you going to the United States? What will you specialize in for your degree? What will be your major?",
        "answer": "The interviewer will ask you these questions one by one. This is just a ‘warm-up’ for the questions to come. You should tell him/her that you have been admitted to an educational institution in the United States. Do not talk a lot. Give short (but not very short) answers, and try not to gibberish since the visa consular will not like that.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "question": "Where did you go to school now? What do you do for a living?",
        "answer": "The interviewer wants to know why you are not joining the workforce, but wish to continue your studies.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "question": "Why are you planning to continue your education? Can you not continue your education in your home country? Why choose the United States of America? Why not choose Canada or Australia?",
        "answer": "He/she will ask about your choice of the US as a study destination instead of another country. Try to give more specific answers.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "question": "How many colleges did you apply to? How many schools did you get admitted to? How many schools rejected you?",
        "answer": "The consular officer wants to shed light on your qualifications as a student and future professional. Keep in mind that students admitted at higher caliber universities will have better chances for a visa. However, you should be honest, when telling how many colleges have rejected you before being admitted to this one. If you lie, the interviewer can easily find out, which may lead to your visa application rejection.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "question": "Do you know your professors at that university? What are their names? What city is your school located?",
        "answer": "If you know very little about the university you have been admitted, it would be better for you if you did some research before you attend your visa interview. The interviewer will ask you about the names of professors or other people in charge of the university. Take care to read about the most famous professors at the university, so you can mention their names and any price they have won, a book they have published or any other achievement of them.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "question": "Have you been to the United States before?",
        "answer": "Answer honestly. Tell about the reasons you have visited the United States before, i.e tourism, training, medical reasons, etc. If you have never been to the United States before you can also say that this is not because you did not want to, but you did not have the chance. Give the impression to the consular that if you don’t get the chance to study there, you would still like to visit the country as a tourist.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "question": "What are your test scores (GRE, GMAT, SAT, TOEFL, IELTS)? What was your previous GPA?",
        "answer": "Even if your university has admitted you, the consular officer will still want to know your likelihood of success at university.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "question": "How do you plan to fund the entire duration of your education?",
        "answer": "With these questions, the interviewer wants to discover how you are planning to fund your stay in the United States. If you have enough savings for the entire period you will be in the United States then present that to the consular officer. Otherwise, if you have a sponsor as parents, cousins, partner, etc., then you will have to present how they will fund your stay in the United States, and if they are capable to do so. If you have won a scholarship for that present documents that prove your statement.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "question": "How much does your school cost? How will you meet these expenses?",
        "answer": "Tell the consular how much does your school cost, and how much you will have to pay for your accommodation and other expenses. Tell him/her how much money you will be receiving each month and try to prove that it will be enough to cover your studies. Even if you are planning to work some student on-campus job, it would be better not to mention it, because this would lead the interviewer to think you might become a burden to the United States public funds.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "question": "What is your sponsor’s occupation?",
        "answer": "They want to know if your sponsor is really capable to cover your expenses.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "question": "Do you have any brother/sister?",
        "answer": "If your parents will be your sponsor, then the interviewer wants to know if they would be capable to do so, or they will have to financially support other people too.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "question": "Have you got any loans? How do you plan on repaying your loan?",
        "answer": "If you do not have any loans you simply say that you do not. Otherwise, honestly tell the interviewer about the quantum of the loan you have applied for and from where you have received the same.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "question": "Will you come back to home during vacations/ holidays?",
        "answer": "Again, the visa officer wants to know about your relations with your home country and your family. Tell them that you will be going back to your holidays to meet family and friends even if you do not. If you plan to stay in the United States during summer or winter holidays and work do not tell that to the interviewer. He will have the impression that you are going to the United States to earn money and that you might stay there even upon the completion of your studies.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "question": "Do you have relatives or friends currently in the US?",
        "answer": "Answer honestly. Even if you have some faraway relatives that you only meet every three-four years, tell the consular about them. Or if you have a friend you have only met once or twice, you will have to tell the consular again.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "question": "What are your plans post-graduation? Do you have a job or career in mind after you graduate?",
        "answer": "Since the F1 Visa is a non-immigrant visa, you will have to convince the consular that you do not plan to remain in the US but rather to return to your home country. If you tell him more about what you plan to do, you will most likely convince him/her that you have no intention to stay in the US after your graduation.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "question": "Do you plan on returning back to your home country? Are you sure you won’t stay in the US? Will you continue to work for your current employer after you graduate?",
        "answer": "Try to tell to the interviewer that you have strong ties to your home country and that you will for sure return. Tell them you have your family, closest friends, or a partner in your home country if you really do. If you have any pet, tell him/her about that too. Mention any property, business, organization, etc., that you have and because of which you will return.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "question": "Why should you be given a student visa?",
        "answer": "This is the very last question you will be asked. Try to put forward a strong case of why you should be issued a visa. Try to make a strong point of your case, and be confident. Once again, do not gibberish. Even while answering this question, try to convince the interviewer by giving him the impression you have no plans to remain in the United States and that you will return to your home country for sure.",
        "difficulty": "Medium"
    }
]